（圭一(けいいち)）その…やっぱり俺…
Uh, it seems like
someone's trying to kill me.
命を狙われているみたいです…
このままいくと
俺も悟史(さとし)と同じ運命をたどると…
At this rate, she said I'll
face the same fate as Satoshi...
（大石(おおいし)）具体的には？
（圭一）転校と…
Be more specific.
Like transfer.
（大石）転校？
Transfer?
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Four, Disturbance
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
あの…すぐ戻りますから
（大石）ああはいかまいませんよ
Um, I'll be right back.
Okay, I don't mind.
ウワッ！
（ﾚﾅ）フフッ…こんばんは
Good evening.
レ…レナ…何しに来たんだよ？
R-Rena...
Why are you here?
Keiichi-kun, have you eaten yet?
圭一君ご飯食べた？
No...
いや…
（ﾚﾅ）フフフッ…じゃ良かった
I'm glad.
お惣菜(そうざい)とか持ってきたの
I brought some side dishes.
お台所とか貸してくれれば
温(あった)めてあげ…
I could warm it in the kitchen...
あっ…ありがたいんだけどさ…
I'm grateful, but it looks
like dinner will be ready soon.
（圭一）もう少しで
夕飯ができるみたいなんだよ
Really?
（ﾚﾅ）そうなの？
（圭一）うちのおふくろってさ
結構おかずをいっぱい作るんだよ
My mom makes
a lot of side dishes, so...
だから…
（ﾚﾅ）本当にお母さん―
Did your mother
really make dinner?
ご飯作ってくれたの？
あっ…あっいやだから…
くれたんじゃなくて今…
Uh, well, she didn't,
but right now...
どうして？
（圭一）えっ？
Why?
どうしてウソをつくのかな？
Why do you lie?
かな？
（圭一）ウソなんか…
Why?
It's not...
ウソだよ！
（圭一）ウッ…
That's a lie!
Your dinner is
cup ramen, isn't it?
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君のお夕飯
カップラーメンでしょう？
豚骨しょうが味
Grilled ginger pork, which
you bought at Seventh Mart.
買ったのはセブンスマート
（圭一）なんで…
How...
（ﾚﾅ）でもそれだけじゃダメだよ
ちゃんと野菜も食べなきゃ
But that's not enough for you.
You should eat vegetables too.
だから圭一君
ここを開けてねっ？
So, Keiichi-kun,
could you open this please?
（チェーンを引く音）
帰ってくれ…
Go home...
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君開けてよ
Keiichi-kun, open it.
Please go home.
頼むから帰ってくれよ
Keiichi-kun...
圭一君…
帰れよ
Go home.
Go home!
帰れー！
- Go home! Go home!
- Ouch! It hurts, Keiichi-kun!
帰れ！帰れ！
（ﾚﾅ）痛い…
痛いよ圭一君…痛い…
（圭一）帰れ！
- Go home! Go home!
- Ouch! It really hurts, Keiichi-kun!
帰れ！
（ﾚﾅ）本当に痛いの 圭一君
（ﾚﾅ）悪ふざけが過ぎたなら謝るよ
- Go home! Go home!
- I'm sorry for fooling around.
帰れ…帰れ！
Go home! Go home!
（ﾚﾅ）痛いの…
ごめんなさいごめんなさい…
- Go home!
- I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
帰れ！帰れ！
Go home! Go home!
ごめんなさいごめんなさい…
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
帰れ！帰れ！
Go home! Go home!
ごめんなさいごめんなさい…
（圭一）帰れ！
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Go home!
（ﾚﾅ）ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Hello? Oishi-san?
もしもし大石さん？
今レナが来ました
Rena was just here.
She came to visit?
（大石）遊びに来たんですか？
（圭一）いえ…
No...
大石さん
話してくださいレナのことを
Oishi-san,
please tell me about Rena.
I don't mind,
but don't tell anyone else.
かまいませんが
他言無用でお願いします
Also, there might be
some assumptions made...
（大石）また内容には一部臆測も
含まれているかもしれませんが
Is that okay?
よろしいですか？
（圭一）はい
Yes.
（雷鳴）
（大石）分かりました
I understand.
あっ…
（大石）正直疑ってます
Truthfully, I'm suspicious.
You mean they're suspects?
やっぱりレナたちが犯人？
No, that's not what I mean.
あ～いやそういう意味ではなく…
“オヤシロさま”をですよ
I'm talking about Oyashiro-sama.
I was wondering if Oyashiro-sama's
curse really exists...
オヤシロさまのたたりって
本当にあるのかな？
…な～んてまあ
And things like that...
The incident with Rena Ryugu
that I told you about before...
先日お話しした竜宮(りゅうぐう)レナの事件
（圭一）茨城の学校で
ガラス窓を割って回ったっていう…
Breaking the school
windows in Ibaraki?
Yes. Actually, there are victims.
（大石）
はい　実は被害者がいるんです
えっ？
（大石）それも―
Plus, three male students she
was close to were hit with a bat.
とても親しかった男子生徒３人が
バットで殴られているんですよ
A bat?
バットで？
But neither the school
nor victims prosecuted...
なのに 学校側も被害者側も
告発していないので―
事件にはなっていないんです
...so it didn't go to court.
この辺りがどうも
関係者は皆さん口が重い
Those involved somehow are
not willing to disclose anything.
被害者の１人は
片目に後遺症を残すくらい―
Though one victim had
a damaged eye from the beating...
殴られているのにもかかわらず
訴えるどころか―
...he didn't go to court
or talk about it.
語ろうともしない
（圭一）うん？
Hello?
（大石）前原(まえばら)君聞こえてますか？
Maebara-san, can you hear me?
なに…
What is she saying?
（圭一）…言ってんだ？
（大石）えっ？
What's that, Maebara-san?
（大石）何ですか？ 前原さん？
（圭一）“ごめんなさい”
（大石）えっ？
I'm sorry...
- Maebara-san? Maebara-san?
- I'm sorry.
前原さん？前原さん？
（圭一）“ごめんなさい”
“ごめんなさい”
（大石）もしも～し！
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Hello?
（圭一）“ごめんなさい”
Kei-chan, good morning!
（魅音(みおん)）圭ちゃん！
（圭一）あっ…
（魅音）おはよう！
圭ちゃんって
野球好きだったっけ？
Did you always like baseball?
I can't concentrate!
Leave me alone!
気が散る！放っといてくれ！
Stop swinging.
やめてよ素振り！
な…何だよ？
（魅音）やめてよ素振り
What?
Stop swinging.
やめてるだろう
I stopped.
I want you to stop for today.
じゃなくて
今日で終わりにしてほしいの
な…なんでだよ？
Why?
I'm not bothering anyone.
別に誰にも迷惑かけてないだろう
You are!
（魅音）かけてる！
俺がいつ誰に迷惑かけたよ？
（魅音）それ…
Who did I bother and when?
That's even
someone else's bat...
人のバットだし
It's something
a transfer student forgot, right?
転校した生徒の忘れ物だろう
（圭一）変わってるよな
兄貴だけ転校して―
It's strange, huh...
Only the brother transferred,
and his little sister didn't, right?
妹は転校しなかったんだろう？
（魅音）知ってたの？
You knew?
Satoshi Hojo.
Satoko's older brother, right?
北条(ほうじょう)悟史　沙都子(さとこ)の兄貴だろう？
去年鬼隠しに遭って消えた
Spirited away
last year and vanished.
I heard that Satoshi
was also practicing swinging.
悟史も
やってたんだってな？素振り
それも失踪の直前に
And right before he went missing.
（圭一）これってさ…
Is this a warning for
Oyashiro-sama's curse?
オヤシロさまの
たたりに遭う前兆ってわけなのか？
とにかく…
Anyway, everyone's afraid.
みんな 怖がってるんだよ
もしもこれが悪ふざけなら―
If you're fooling around, then you
have to stop imitating Satoshi!
悟史のマネは絶対にやめて！
先に言っとく
俺は悟史のことは何も知らない
I'll say this first. I don't
know anything about Satoshi.
Everyone's hiding it.
みんなが隠してたからな！
隠してたってわけじゃ…
We weren't hiding it...
You didn't want to scare me?
怖がらせたくなかったってのか？
I'm shut out just for that reason?
それだけが理由で
俺だけのけ者かよ？
No, I didn't mean...
いやそんなつもりじゃ…
（圭一）ダム現場で
事件がなかったかって聞いたよな
I asked if something
happened at the dam site.
You said no!
（圭一）
“ない”って言ったじゃねえか！
バラバラ殺人があったのによ！
Despite the dismemberment!
You liar!
ウソつき野郎が！
Sorry, I didn't mean to lie...
ごめん　ウソってわけじゃ…
仲間ってのは
隠し事なんかなしだろう
Friends don't hide things
from each other, right?
そうだろう？
Isn't that right?
だからお前らは仲間じゃない！
That's why you're not my friends!
け…圭ちゃんそんなのって…
K-Kei-chan...
That's not...
あ～それに見舞いのおはぎ
あれうまかったぜ
Oh, the ohagi that
you gave me was good.
So good it made me bleed.
血が出るくらいにな
やったのはどっちだ？
Who did it?
You or Rena?
お前か？レナか？
俺を消そうとしても
簡単にはいかないからな
You can't easily get
rid of me even if you try.
悟史を消せたように
簡単に消せると思うなよ！
Don't think you can get rid
of me as easily as Satoshi.
お前が
殺されたダム工事の現場監督と―
I know that you
got into several fights...
何度も取っ組み合いのケンカを
してたってのも知ってる
...with the dam construction
director who got killed.
隠しきれると思ったのかよ？
You thought you could hide it?
どうしてそんなことまで…
How do you even know that?
行こうぜ
授業に遅れるとマズイだろう
Let's go.
It'd suck if we're late.
（泣き声）
ひどいよ圭ちゃん
That's cruel, Kei-chan.
I see...
（魅音）そっか…
The person who told you
everything was that guy.
圭ちゃんに全部バラしたの
あの野郎か…
I should've killed him back then.
あのとき殺しとくんだったなぁ
今年で定年だからって
容赦してやった恩も忘れやがって
He forgot how I forgave him since
he was going to retire this year.
Damn.
ちくしょう…
ちくしょうあのじじい！
Damn that old bastard.
I'll definitely kill him.
絶対に殺してやる！
Old bastard...
You mean Oishi-san?
じじいって大石さんの…
Why does she have a cleaver?
なんでナタなんか…
I found you, Keiichi-kun.
圭一君見ぃ～つけた
ハッ…何の用だよ？
What do you want?
My home is the same way.
圭一君と同じ帰り道だよ
じゃそのナタは何だよ？
Then what's that cleaver for?
What is it?
何だよ？
Keiichi-kun, isn't
something bothering you?
圭一君悩んでることが
あるんじゃないかな？
怖いんだよね？圭一君
（圭一）アアッ…
You're scared, aren't you?
I-I'm not scared...
怖くなんか…
（ﾚﾅ）
悟史君が転校しちゃったときは―
When Satoshi-kun transferred,
I really regretted it.
本当に後悔したんだよ
I really regretted not listening
to what was bothering him.
レナが
相談に乗ってあげられればって―
すごく後悔した
転校って
鬼隠しのことなんだろう？
Transferred... You mean spirited
away by the demon, right?
そうだろう？
悟史を消したのは誰だよ？
Who got rid of Satoshi?
Was it you? Or Mion?
レナか？魅音か？
それとも村の誰かか？答えろよ！
Or was it someone from
the village? Answer me!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
何を言ってるのか分からないなぁ
I'll say it so you understand.
じゃ分かるように言ってやる！
連続怪死事件の犯人は誰だ？
Who committed
the serial murders?
You misunderstand.
圭一君は勘違いしてるよ
（圭一）えっ？
The suspect isn't human.
人間の犯人なんかいない
Oyashiro-sama
decides everything.
全ては
オヤシロさまが決めることだもの
Oyashiro-sama's
curse is superstition!
（圭一）オヤシロさまの
たたりなんて迷信だ！
You don't believe
in Oyashiro-sama?
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君は
信じないの？オヤシロさま
H-How could
I believe such a thing?
し…信じられるはずないだろう
そんなの！
Oyashiro-sama does exist.
いるよオヤシロさま
（圭一）アア…
Has someone
apologized to you?
圭一君さ
誰かに謝られたことない？
And for a long, long time?
それもずっと…ず～っと…
（ﾚﾅ）レナの所にも
来たんだよオヤシロさま
Oyashiro-sama came to me too.
だからレナは転校して
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に帰ってきたの
That's why I transferred and
came back to Hinamizawa.
Only I can listen
to your problems.
圭一君の相談に乗れるのは私だけ
I won't let you transfer.
圭一君を転校なんかさせないから
さあ話して
（圭一）何だよ…
Now, tell me.
What?
I'll listen.
レナが聞いてあげる
助けてあげるから
I'll save you.
So tell me.
ねえ話して
ウ…ウソだろう…
No way!
ンンッ！何か俺に用かよ？
What do you want?
I'll hit you on the foreheads
next, you bastards!
次は眉間にお見舞いするぞ
この野郎！
When They Cry
I think you should stay laid down.
（ﾚﾅ）
横になってたほうがいいと思うな
（圭一）ハッ…レナ…
Rena...
お医者さんに電話したから
もうすぐ来ると思う
I called the doctor,
so he should be here soon.
Why are you here?
どうしてここに？
Pardon me!
（魅音）おジャマしま～す
（ドアの開く音）
Mion? Why?
魅音…なんで？
Your family wasn't here,
so I called her.
お家(うち)の人いなかったから
私がね電話したの
Hey, you look okay.
あれ？元気そうじゃん
心配して損したかな
Did I waste time worrying?
Rena, did you call the director?
（魅音）レナ監督には電話した？
うん魅(み)ぃちゃんに電話したあと
すぐ来るって言ってたよ
After I called you.
The director will be here soon.
Who's the director?
“監督”って何だよ？
（魅音）アハハハッ…
圭ちゃん知らないの？
You don't know? If I say
director, I mean the director.
監督っていったら監督だよ
You're into baseball
nowadays, right?
圭ちゃん
最近は野球に凝ってるんだよね？
That'll make the director happy.
監督それ聞いたら喜ぶと思うな
（ﾚﾅ）うん
So who's the director?
だから 監督って誰だよ？
アハハハッ…監督は監督さんだよ
The director is the director.
So who is that?
だから誰だよ？
お…お前ら…
Y-You guys...
（魅音）そうだ監督が来る前に
済ませとくかな罰ゲーム
Oh, yeah!
Let's finish the punishment
game before that.
罰ゲーム？
（ﾚﾅ）おはぎの宿題…
The game?
The ohagi homework.
I'm sure you forgot about it, huh?
確か忘れてたよね？
アアッ…何のマネだよ？
- What is this?
- Don't move.
動かないでね罰ゲームだから
It's a punishment game.
何だよそれ…何のマネだよ？
What is that?
What are you doing?
圭ちゃん分かってんでしょう？
Kei-chan, you know, right?
何が…何が分かってるって…
What? What do I know?
（大石）薬物を疑いましたが
We suspected drugs, but we
couldn't detect anything like that.
そういう たぐいの物は
検出できませんでした
ンンッ！
（魅音）ハハッ…観念しなって
Give up.
やめろ…やめろー！
Stop!
Stop it!
（殴る音）
ハァ…ハァ…
They came.
来やがった
レナと魅音は犯人の一味
Rena and Mion are suspects.
ほかにも大人が４～５人以上
白いワゴン車を所有
There are more than four or
five adults who own a white van.
Tomitake-san's death
was from an unknown drug.
富竹(とみたけ)さんの死は
未知の薬物によるもの
証拠の注射器はこれです
The proof is this syringe.
Why?
どうして…
どうしてこんなことに…
Why did it turn out like this?
（村人）いたぞ裏口だ！
He's here! The back door!
Just a second.
（刑事）少々お待ちください
Oh, Oishi-san,
you have a call from the public.
（刑事）あっ大石さん
一般の方から外線です
（大石）ああこりゃどうも
（刑事）公衆からですよ
Oh, thank you.
It's from a public phone.
This is Oishi, hello?
大石ですもしもし
（圭一）お…大石さんですか？
O-Oishi-san?
前原さん？何かありましたか？
Maebara-san?
Did something happen?
あっその…ウウッ…
（大石）うん？
Uh...
What happened?
何があったんです？
Hinamizawa telephone booth
What happened?
あ…あ…あの…俺…
Hinamizawa telephone booth
U-U-U-Um, I...
Calm down, Maebara-san.
落ち着いて前原さん
今そこに近場の警官を行かせます
I'll send a nearby officer now.
I'll be there right away too.
私もすぐそっちに行きますから
Um, that's probably useless...
あっその…多分ムリです
間に合わな…
It'll be too late.
There's only one phone booth
there. I sent a car. Five minutes.
（大石）落ち着いて前原さん
今どういう状況なんです？
There's only one phone booth
there. I sent a car. Five minutes.
Calm down, Maebara-san.
There's only one phone booth
there. I sent a car. Five minutes.
How's the situation right now?
That's too long! How many
people are in the car?
かかりすぎです！
警邏(けいら)には何人乗ってます？
（刑事）２人
Two.
Did you call the resident officer?
（大石）
雛見沢の駐在さんに電話は？
定時巡回の時間で不在です
He's on scheduled patrol.
Kuma-chan,
please prepare a car!
熊(くま)ちゃん車を回してください
Yes, sir!
（熊谷(くまがい)）了解ッス！
もしもし前原さん
今そこに警官が向かってます
Hello, Maebara-san?
There's an officer
headed there now.
２～３分で到着しますから
It'll be two to three minutes.
Maebara-san,
who's the suspect?
前原さん
犯人は誰です？何人なんです？
How many?
（圭一）お…俺も最初は…
I-I also thought at first that
the suspect was human...
人間が犯人なんだと思いまし…
ウウッ…
But actually...
だけどやっぱり…
...Oyashiro-sama seems to exist.
オヤシロさまってのは
いるんだと思います
- Right now...
- Maebara-san?
今…
（大石）前原さん…
ウウッ…
ず～っとつけてくるんですよ
It keeps following me...
Even though I run,
run, run, and run...
走っても走っても
走っても走っても…
...it sticks to me like a shadow.
影みたいにぴったりくっついて…
Little by little, little by little...
少しずつ…少しずつ俺の背中に
にじり寄ってくるんです
...it keeps coming
closer to my back.
（せきこみ）
（大石）前原さん
Maebara-san, is he...
そいつは今ひょっとして
前原さんの…
Right now,
by any chance, is your...
後ろに…すぐ後ろに…
Behind me... Right behind me...
ハァハァ…
（大石）誰がいるんです？
Who's there?
振り向けるわけないじゃないですか
How can I look back?
振り向いたら俺…俺…
If I turn around, I'II... I'II...
I know you're afraid!
But I want you to tell me!
怖いのは分かります
でも教えてほしい
Just turn around a little bit!
ちょっと振り返るだけでいいんです
Who's behind you,
Maebara-san?
前原さんの後ろに
誰が…誰がいるんです？
Maebara-san, you're not...
前原さんあんたまさか…
アアッ…
（大石）喉を―
...clawing your throat, are you?
ひっかいたりしては
いないでしょうね？
アアッ…
（大石）もしもし前原さん！
Hello, Maebara-san? Maebara...
前原…
（圭一）ご…な…い…
Sorry...
Oishi-san, the car is ready.
（熊谷）大石さん車ＯＫッス！
Oishi-san!
（熊谷）大石さん！
“ごめんなさい”だ…
Sorry?
June 1983
Report
In Shishibone City, Hinamizawa,
female students were murdered.
（大石）鹿骨(ししぼね)市雛見沢で
女子生徒殺人事件が発生
容疑者は前原圭一
The suspect is Keiichi Maebara.
Inviting over two classmates,
Rena Ryugu and Mion Sonozaki...
自宅にクラスメートの女子２名―
竜宮レナ園崎(そのざき)魅音を呼び寄せ
金属バットで撲殺
...he beat them
to death with a bat.
He fled and was found collapsed
in a phone booth by officers...
容疑者は犯行現場から逃走後―
警邏中の警察官に電話ボックス内で
倒れているのを発見されるも―
...dying 24 hours
later at the hospital.
24時間後に収容先の病院にて死亡
検視の結果
死因は出血性ショック死
The autopsy said death was
caused by shock from blood loss.
自らの爪で喉を引き裂き―
By slitting his throat
with his own nails...
その結果
出血多量で死に至ったもよう
...he died from
losing too much blood.
No sign of drugs was found.
薬物などの使用は認められず
（シャッター音）
（大石）その後容疑者の自室から
Later, a handwritten memo was
found in the suspect's room.
直筆のメモが発見される
メモはＢ５の大学ノートを
半分に裂いた物２枚で構成され
It was made of two sheets of B5
college-ruled paper cut in half...
...and taped behind
the clock on the wall.
壁の時計の裏に貼り付けられていた
That memo must've
originally been one B5 page...
そのメモは元は
Ｂ５のページに書かれた物を―
...which was torn to remove a few
lines in the middle of the page.
何者かが
真ん中の数行を削除するために―
破り捨てたのではないかと
推測される
From the large amount of tape
residue behind the clock...
また 時計裏に付着していた
大量の粘着テープ跡から―
メモ以外にも何かが
貼り付けられていたのではないかと
...it could be assumed that
something else was also taped.
考えられる
以下がそのメモの内容である
The following is the memo.
“私前原圭一は
命を狙われています”
I, Keiichi Maebara,
am in danger of getting killed.
“なぜ誰に命を
狙われているのかは分かりません”
I don't know why or who.
The only thing I know...
“ただひとつ分かることは―”
“オヤシロさまのたたりと
関係があるということです”
...is that it has something to do
with Oyashiro-sama's curse.
Rena and Mion are suspects.
“レナと魅音は犯人の一味”
There are more than four or
five adults who own a white van.
“ほかにも大人が４～５人以上
白いワゴン車を所有”
The following is the second page.
以下は２枚目
“どうして
こんなことになったのか―”
I don't know how things
turned out like this.
“私には分かりません”
（圭一）
これをあなたが読んだなら―
I'll probably be dead by
the time you read this.
そのとき私は死んでいるでしょう
To the one reading this,
please uncover the truth.
これを読んだあなた
どうか真相を暴いてください
That is my only wish.
それだけが私の望みです
前原圭一
Keiichi Maebara.
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
I want you to stare at the real me.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
見つめてほしい本当の自分を…
I want you to forgive
the whimsical you.
許してほしい
気まぐれなあなたを…
分かってほしいもう１人の私を…
I want you
to understand the other me.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
The Cotton Drifting
Chapter One, Jealousy.
Chapter One, Jealousy
The Cotton Drifting
Chapter One, Jealousy.
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？